行动代号
Operation...
破冰号
Icebreaker.
感觉怎么样  这个名字我们没有用过吧
How we liking that? We never used that before, did we?
-这不是清新薄荷糖的名字吗  -什么
- Isn't it the name of a breath mint? - What?
"透心凉"  是吗  清新薄荷糖
"Icebreakers", right? Breath mint?
没有人会那么想的
Nobody's gonna be thinking that.
他们会想到一只游走在北极的大头破冰船
They'll think about a big ass ship in the north pole, breaking ice.
就你而已  我会想到清新薄荷行动
Says you. I'm gonna be thinking "operation breath mint."
每次跟你一起外勤
I'm thinking "operation breath mint"
我就会想到清新薄荷糖好吧
Every time we're on a stakeout together. All right
你嘴里那味儿能把人熏死
Your breath could knock a buzzard off a shit wagon.
好吧
All right.
行动代号待定
"Operation TBD."
格米  都被你搅和的
Thanks for nothing, Gomie.
不管怎样  先跟
Anyway. Say hello to...
多明戈·加拉多·莫利纳  疯狂小八打个招呼
Domingo Gallardo Molina, aka "Crazy 8."
他可比普通的线人精明的多
Smarter than your average cheese-eater.
他成为线人的时候不过是个小混混
I turned him out at the street-level,
但是这哥们向杰佛逊学习  向上拼搏
But this dude's like the Jeffersons: movin' on up.
每次他供出来的小毒贩后
Every small-time dealers he'd throw at us,
都接手了他们的客户
He'd end up snaking their customers.
现在他被证实失踪了  可能已死亡
It turns out he's missing, presumed dead.
在荒郊野岭发现了他的车
Found his car out in the boonies.
最后一个被他供出来的正是他自己的表弟
Last guy he ratted out was none other than his cousin,
埃米利奥·小山
Emilio koyama.
你认为是他表弟发现后向他报复吗
You thinking the cousin found out and took revenge?
有可能  结果他表弟也失踪了
Could be. Turns out he's missing, too.
一般情况  我会说有人为民除了害
And normally, I'd say someone did the world a favor.
但是在我们线人车中
But our snitch's car?
找到了两克冰毒
Turns out we find two grams of meth in it,
我们带到了实验室
we take it to the lab.
实验人员告诉我们这是有史以来最纯的冰毒
They come back, they tell us it is the purest they have ever seen.
99.1%
99.1%.
我们的化学家完败
I mean our chemist was  blown away.
说这个纯度是他的极限
He said he couldn't do the same thing better.
更糟的是  这并非出自墨西哥的超级实验室
Worse yet, it didn't come out of some superlab in Mexico.
我们认为制毒地点就在这儿
We're thinking this was cooked right here,
毒品交易的大本营
in the land of enchantment.
汽车似乎被遗弃在一个制毒地点
Car was abandoned at what appears to be a cook site.
这是遗留下来的唯一证物
This is the only other thing left behind.
我们正把它送到匡狄克
We're sending it off to Quantico,
看能否找到什么线索
see if they can pull something off it.
与此同时  我们的人清洗了过滤器
Meantime, our guys swabbed the filter element
发现了同样99.1%纯度的冰毒
Found the same 99.1 meth.
大家注意了
So be on notice.
有新毒贩来了
We got new players in town.
我们不知道他们是谁  来自何方
We don't know who they are, where they come from...
但是他们有高级制毒技术装备
But they possess an extremely high skill-set.
我个人的看法
Me personally?
我认为阿尔布开克来了位重量级人物
I'm thinking Albuquerque just might have a new kingpin.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
绝
命
毒
师
第一季
第四集
翻译：小老虎    小松狮    Marvin    夜    缭乱
■
翻译：joanna    时间轴：小老虎     特效：Will
校对：小路      后期：冰河       监制：蛐蛐
■
天呐  沃尔特  你把鸡肉都烤糊了
Jesus. Walt, you're burning the shit out of them.
该死
Oh. Damn it.
斯凯  还有鸡肉吗
Hey, Sky, you got any more chicken?
艾梅里尔要重新烤一批
Emeril here is gonna need a fresh pack.
恩  看起来不错
All right, looking good.
这个是不是低脂蛋黄酱卷心菜沙拉
Is this low-fat mayonnaise in the cole slaw?
我不知道  商店买的
I don't know. It's store-bought.
汉克  再来瓶啤酒怎么样
Hank, you need another beer?
教皇在帽子里大便了吗
Does the pope shit in his hat?
汉克  我不认为他真这么做了
I don't think that he does, Hank.
我认为大家都希望你停止谈论这个话题
And I think everybody would like it if you'd stop saying that.
-玛丽  再来点儿酒
- Marie, some more wine, maybe?
-不用了  谢谢
- I'm all right, thanks.
我想来瓶啤酒
Hey, I want a beer.
我还想让沙尼娅·吐温给我个"手活"呢
Yeah. I want Shania Twain to give me a tuggie.
猜怎么着  那也没有发生
Guess what? That ain't happening, either.
-给你来点儿苏打水怎么样  -好吧
- How about some more soda? - Yeah, sure.
亲爱的  你要来儿什么吗
Honey, do you need anything?
-沃尔特  不用了
- No, Walt. Thank you.
-好的  我去去就回
- Okay. I'll be right back.
什么  你开玩笑吧
What, are you kidding me?
你看起来简直像个电影明星
You look like a damn movie star, man.
成群结队的姑娘会等着你
Girls gotta be lining up left and right.
-告诉这小子他有多帅  -他可爱极了
- Tell him how good-looking he is. - He's adorable.
他不不想被人说成可爱  他要性感火辣
He don't wanna be friggin' adorable. He wants to be hot.
听到我说的吗  那才是女人的想法
Anyway you see what I'm talking about? That's a female perspective.
她本来是想这么说的
She supposed to say that.
听着  小伙子不用看起来像
Look, a guy doesn't have to look like, uh...
查尔登·海斯顿一样才能赢取女孩芳心
Charlton heston... I'm talking "moses" days...
我说的是在他那个年代
To get a girl, all right?
你需要
You just gotta have...
自信满满
Confidence.
自信外加坚持不懈
Confidence and... and persistence.
这些是你所需要的
That's what I'm talking about.
我用尽手段来追求你姨妈玛丽
I chased your aunt Marie here all over creation.
我不断请求她和我约会  她一直拒绝
I kept bugging her for a date. She kept saying no.
我是不是请求了大概50次
What, did I ask you like 50 times?
那是在跟踪法被强化以前
It was before they tightened the stalking laws.
不管怎么说  让你老爹说说吧
Anyway, how about your dad here?
沃尔特也有段精彩的故事呢
Right there's a good story, Walt.
说说看你怎么认识斯凯勒的
Tell him how you met Skyler.
妈妈在洛斯阿拉莫斯当服务生
Mom was a waitress in Los Alamos.
然后爸爸向你表白...
And dad said that thing to you...
事实上  你妈妈不是服务生
Actually, your mother wasn't a waitress.
那不过是暑期的兼职
It was a summer job,
她是老板娘
And she was the hostess,
还负责收银
And she also worked the cash register.
我以前经常去那里
And I used to go in there a lot
因为离实验室很近
Because it was close enough to the lab
骑自行车就能到
where I could ride my bicycle.
有一次我注意到了她
And once I noticed her...
我走进去以后
It got to be so that I would only go in
发现她在里面上班
When I knew she was working.
空下来的时候  她会靠着着柜台
When it was slow, she would lean against the counter,
做她的填字游戏
Doing her crossword puzzles,
不过是偷偷的
But kind of hiding it, right,
一边假装还在工作
Pretending that she was still working.
有一次被我看到了
And once I caught on to that,
我吃烤芝士三明治的时候也做填字游戏
I would do crossword puzzles while I ate my grilled cheese sandwich.
就这样每天午餐的时候
It got so that everyday at lunch,
我们都一起做纽约时报上的填字游戏
We would both be doing the New York Times crossword puzzle
两人隔着10英尺远
Ten feet from each other.
终于
Eventually,
我发现她在看我
I caught her looking over at me.
于是我就说  请问
So, I began saying, "excuse me,
横向14那个7个字母的单词  你填什么
Fourteen across, seven-letter word for whatchamacallit.
我能问问你填了什么吗
"May I ask what you wrote down?"
我们就这样聊了起来
And well, that got us talking.
天啊  告诉你  其实不会做填字游戏
Boy, I tell you, I was... I was terrible at those puzzles.
可能我连一个都没做完过
I don't think that I finished even one of them.
但你妈妈很在行
But your mother would do them in ink.
很厉害啊
Very smooth.
打赌你没想到你老爸也有这招吧
I'll bet you didn't think your old man had it in him?
但这就是我想说的  这就叫坚持
But that's what I'm talking about. That's persistence.
看见没  一旦你看准了某样东西
You see? Once you set your cap for something,
或是某个人  你就得
Or somebody, you gotta just, you know...
斯凯勒
Wow, Skyler?
妈妈  你还好吗
Mom, are you all right?
亲爱的  没关系
Shh, honey. It's okay.
你怎么了
What's the matter?
怎么回事
What is it?
你问他
Ask him.
她什么意思
What's she talking about?
沃尔特
Walt.
我得了癌症
I have cancer.
肺癌
Lung cancer.
太糟糕了
It's bad.
问问他知道多久了
Ask him how long he's known.
我想大概有一个月  或者
I guess a month, maybe, or...
看在老天的的份上  沃尔特
For god sakes, Walt.
我们居然还若无其事地 坐在外面在野餐
We're just sitting out there having a cookout like nothing's going on?
他还让我保证不告诉任何人
He made me promise not to tell anybody.
天啊  过去的48小时太难熬了
Christ, these last 48 hours.
而且现在是周末
And it's the weekend,
我都没办法联系上他的医生
So I couldn't even get his doctor on the phone.
伙计  我是说  你为什么不想告诉任何人
Buddy, why... I mean, why wouldn't you want to tell anybody?
沃尔特  你没看见吗
Walt, don't you see?
每个人都想帮你
Everybody just wants to help you.
我们是一家人
We're family.
我们会一起度过难关的
We get through these things together.
我不明白
I mean, I don't get... you know...
肺癌
Lung cancer?
怎么可能  你甚至都不抽烟
How could that happen? You don't smoke.
我在想这跟20年前
I'm thinking that this goes back 20 years
跟应用实验室有关
Maybe to the applications lab.
他们整天接触那些化学药品
All those chemicals they had you working around?
我们一直都有很好的预防措施
We always took the proper precautions.
有次你抱怨过  他们没给你配备正确的
One time you complained they didn't give you the right kind of...
我不知道  某种防毒面罩什么的
I don't know, some kind of ventilation hood or something.
-然后你就一直头痛  -亲爱的  不是那样的
- And then the headaches. - Honey, it wasn't that.
他们以为就能这样不负责吗
How do they think they can get away with this?
我们应该雇个律师
We should hire a lawyer.
首先  我们先治病
First, let's deal with this.
好吗  walt下一步怎么做
Okay? So what's the next step for Walt?
肯定是换个医生  对吗
Certainly a second opinion, right?
没错
Right.
没错  当然
Right. Absolutely.
好的  所以明天一早
Okay. So first thing tomorrow,
我会跟放射科医师谈谈
I talk to my radiologists,
我们会给你找到最好的
We find you the best...
治疗肿瘤的梦幻团队
The oncology dream team.
我想去看看小沃尔特
I wanna go check on Walt Jr.
我去看看
I'm gonna see...
不知道能不能劝他也加入我们
If I can talk him into, I don't know, joining us.
我真不是有意  让他在这种情况下知道的
I really didn't mean for him to find out that way.
沃尔特  无论发生什么
Walt...Whatever happens...
我真不想这么说  但是
I hope this goes without saying, but...
无论发生什么
Whatever happens...
我想你知道
I want you to know that...
我会帮你照顾好你的家庭的
I'll always take care of your family.
看看这些假冒的果酱馅饼
Yo, check out these fake pop tarts.
很好吃
These are mad tight.
-不用了谢谢  让开  -不吃是你的损失
- No, thanks, man. Pass.  - Your loss.
这些可是加拿大货  进口的
These are from Canada or something. Imported.
你的走廊怎么了  伙计
Yo, what happened to your hallway, man?
-是天花板塌了吗  -没错
- Did the ceiling fall down or... - Oh, yeah...
我觉得整栋房子都在下沉
I think the house is just settling.
到处都在掉东西下来
It's been caving in left and right.
正好打着我的眼睛
Hit me in the eye.
是香蕉
It's bananas.
我的人说不定可以帮你
Yo, my pops could fix you up.
他是那种承包商之类的
He's like a contractor or something.
那行啊  我应该记他的号码
Right on. I should grab that number.
说说  杰西  你还在制冰毒吗
Say, Jesse. You still cook a little crystal?
算是吧
Could be, yeah.
你也清楚  我总是听说
You know, from time to time.
听说你没了搭档
I heard you lost your partner.
埃米利奥
Emilio.
-他不是被关起来了吗
- Didn't he get locked up?
-伙计  没  他出来了
- No, man. He's out.
他堂兄保释的  我猜他已经出了城
His cousin bailed him out. I think he skipped town or something.
我一点都不知道
I don't know about any of that.
这些天我都忙着自己的事呢
I've been just kinda doing my own thing these days so.
你那儿有点货吧  伙计
But you maybe got some crystal, man?
因为我要去酒会玩玩
cause I could seriously go for a bowl
去爽一下
You know? Take the edge off.
周日夜派对哦
Hell, yeah. Sunday night bowl, yo.
算碰巧吧
Maybe it just so happens that...
我最近刚做了一批货
I just recently cooked the best batch ever.
嗯  用了这种全新的配法
Oh, yeah. Came up with this whole new recipe.
更像是一种分子式
It's more like a formula.
从化学上讲更科学
It's like way, way more chemically...
试制非常成功
You know, it's just the bomb.
但是  我搞不懂
But, you know, I don't know,
我后来一直在想停一段时间
I've been thinking lately I'll just lay off of it for a while.
因为我都快被它弄出妄想症了
cause lately it's been making me paranoid, so...
所以呢  为了健康考虑  就没再嗑了
You know, for, like... like healthwise, just lay off.
喂  你是不想跟咱分享吧  伙计
Yo, if you're not into sharing, man,
直接请我们滚蛋就行了  潇洒一点
Just tell us to piss off. It's cool.
我们可不想拖泥带水的
We don't need no soap opera.
伙计  随你啦
Yeah, man. Whatever.
别  没事啊
No, no. It's all good.
我  我就是说
You know, I... I'm just saying...
我这还有很多大麻呢
Hey, I got... I got plenty of pot.
嗯  我要闪人了  伙计
Yeah, I think I'll bounce, man.
说的是
Yeah, sounds about right.
喂  喂
Hey, yo, yo.
兄弟
Hey, homes.
我开玩笑呢
I'm joking.
行了  我就是逗你们玩
Okay, I'm totally joking with you.
别闹了  坐下
You kidding? Sit down.
极品冰毒
Best scante ever.
把吸管拿来
Grab that pipe.
需要帮忙吗
Do you need some help?
不用  亲爱的  我很好
No, I'm fine, honey.
很好  只是
I'm fine. Just...
一点个人隐私
Privacy.
谢谢
Thanks.
-需要的话  我就在门外  -好
- I'm right outside if you need me. - OK
嗯  周五任何时间都绝对可以
Yeah, anytime on Friday is absolutely fine.
太谢谢你安排我们了
Thank you so much for working us in.
记在信用卡可以么
Can I just put that on a credit card?
很好
Great.
太好了
Perfect.
那我们在周五早晨
Okay, so we will see you
十点四十五分见你
At 10:45 on Friday morning.
非常感谢你
Thank you so much.
亲爱的
Honey.
有位顶尖的肿瘤学家
The best oncologist...
不只在新墨西哥州
I mean, not even just in New Mexico,
而是位列全国前十名
But one of the top ten in the entire nation...
他叫戴尔克沃利医生
His name is Dr. Delcavoli.
周五我们去见他
And we see him on Friday.
玛丽真的在帮我们
I mean, Marie really came through for us.
她老板跟她打过了电话
She had her boss call and...
不错
OK. This is good.
从这次开始  事情会
From here on out, I mean, things are gonna...
什么记在信用卡做上呢
What's that we're putting on a credit card?
类似保证金之类的东西
It's just a deposit kind of thing.
-要多少  -5000美元
- How much of a deposit? - It's $5,000.
五千美元
Five thousand?
做什么用  仅仅是开个头吗
And what's that? Just to start?
就告诉一些我已经知道的东西吗
Just to tell me what I already know?
沃尔特  他不在我们医保系统里
Walt, he's not in our HMO, okay?
就这样了  我们会慢慢搞清楚的
So be it. We'll figure it out.
拜托  别钻钱眼里了行吗
Come on. Don't get hung up on money here.
我们可以找汉克借啊
We can always borrow from Hank.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
不  我只是
No, I just...
我们绝不那样做
We're not gonna do that.
那我们可以向你母亲借
Well, maybe we can ask your Mom.
你有没有跟她打过电话
Have you even called her yet?
先不管这事  你起码应该告诉她
Regardless, you're gonna have to tell her.
-我是愿意做的  -好  我来打
- I'm willing to do it...  - I'll call.
我不想让我俩总想着钱
I don't even want us thinking about money.
现在不是钱的问题  不是
Money is not the issue here. It's not.
我来管保证金的事
Okay. Okay. I'll take care of the deposit.
我从养老金里预支
I'll borrow it from my pension.
怎么了
What's up?
我好像听到了老鼠
I thought I heard mice.
我们要这些就够了对吧
That's all we need, huh?
怎么了  朋友
So, what's up, pal?
你到底是怎么了
What the hell's wrong with you?
什么
What?
你表现得
You're acting all...you're
为什么你表现得这么
Why are you acting so...
古怪
Weird?
-孩子  -你就像是都没发生一样
- Son. - You're acting like nothing is going on.
怎么这样
Come on!
要我过去揍你吗
Am I gonna have to come down there and whip your ass?
跟你说点别的
And let me tell you something else.
我可不是为了慈善才这么做的对吧
I'm not doing this for charity, right?
我可是办公室里最棒的
I'm the best he's got in that office.
他清楚得很  我知道
He knows it, I know it.
我得要个上档次的价格
I expect to be paid to a level comens...
我说  戴夫
I said, Dave,
你觉得四万块的分红够了吗
Do you think 40 grand is a proper bonus?
还不到这个季度
That's less than 10% of
我给你们下的订单的百分之十
What I booked for you guys this quarter.
我才不会坐视你们对我不敬
I'm not going to sit here and be disrespected.
他个白痴
Oh, he's shitin bricks.
你知道他是什么货色
Oh, you know he is.
他就是一废物  而我能畅行无阻
Yeah, that man lives in fear. I'll go across town.
我去哪都行
Hell, I could go anywhere.
去霍夫曼戈登布拉德利  或是索尔彻  戈德堡韦恩也行
Hoffman-gordon-bradley or sorcher, even goldberg-wayne.
只要我肯去  他们就会让我做合伙人
They'd make me a partner just for walking in the damn door.
他们见了我就这么欣喜若狂
That's how ecstatic they'd be.
兄弟  太好了
Hells, yes, brother-man!
瞧瞧这女人
Check this chick out.
谁
Who?
伙计  她就是头猪
Buddy, she's a cow.
斯泰茜是头猪
Stacey's a cow.
我们讨论的是猪圈的肥猪
We're talking major barnyard boo-hog.
把她在面粉里滚一滚
Roll her in flour and look for
之前看看哪儿湿了
the wet spot before you hit that, man.
明白吗
You know what I'm saying?
她不是很容易摆脱的
That's kind of sick is not a wash-off
-先生  -好吧
- Sir? -Right
-先生  -是吗
- Sir? -Oh, yeah?
抱歉  你好
Sorry. Hi.
-能为您做点什么  -哪个
- What can I do for you? - Which dude?
那个长得像蜥蜴的家伙吗
The dude that looked like a lizard?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我要开张这全数金额的现金支票
I would like a cashier's check in the full amount
收款人是新墨西哥州肿瘤病友  谢谢
Made out to oncology partners of New Mexico, please.
是肿  瘤
Oh, that's o-n-c-o-l-o-g-y.
对  是这么写
Yeah, you got it.
我就不明白他们为什么要强迫你
I don't understand why they're forcing you
在短笛和双簧管之间选一个
To choose between the piccolo and the oboe.
那俩种你吹都很够格
You show so much promise with both.
他们不许木管乐器有交叉
They can't have any switching between woodwinds
因为不管怎么分配  总会有个被漏掉
Because no matter how divided up, someone would be left out.
规定就是规定
Well, rules are rules, I guess.
是啊  规定就是规定  我完全赞成
Sure, rules and rules. I'm all for that.
不过我跟你说  你的双簧管吹得非常棒
But I'm telling you, you really shine on that oboe.
你很有天赋  我可不只是说说
You have real talent, and I'm not just saying that.
谢谢
Thanks.
彭伯顿老师怎么样
What about Mr. Pemberton?
他对你关注够多吗
Is he giving you enough individual attention?
我得说够多了
I'd have to say so.
每次练习他都尽量
He tries to talk to each one of us
至少和每个人都谈一次
At least once during every practice.
那很好  反馈很重要
That's good. Feedback's important.
那是关键  我认为
It's key, I think.
那你的足球练得怎样了
Hey, so how was soccer practice?
好像是从我们的后院传来的
I think that was in our backyard.
谁在那
Who's there?
你到底在这里干什么
What the hell are you doing out here?
爸
Hey, dad.
妈
Hey, mom.
你们添置了新的庭院摆设
You got new patio furniture.
正好夹了
Right on!
我的腿
My leg.
你觉得这次是怎么回事
What do you think it could be?
天知道  我又不是专家
God knows I'm no expert.
我不知道  兴奋剂  镇静剂
I don't know. Uppers, downers?
我都能猜   你不也能吗
Your guess is as good as mine.
我想我们得看看他胳膊上有没有针孔
I think we should check his arms for needle marks.
要让他住下吗
Do we let him stay?
长老会教堂有些集会
The presbyterian church has those meetings.
也许某些条件下
So maybe on condition, you know?
他会同意参加的
If he agrees to attend?
我只是不知道该怎么跟Jake说
I just don't know what to tell Jake.
晚上好
Good evening.
睡好了吗
Well, sleep well?
几点吃晚饭
What time's, uh... what time is dinner?
还得一小时吧
In about an hour.
你要是愿意我可以帮你把衣服洗了
You know, I could wash those clothes if you'd like.
看起来有些脏了
They look a little lived in.
不用  这挺好
No, that's cool.
不然晚一点再说
Maybe later.
我们不能再这么做了
We are not doing this again.
-亚当  -不行
- Adam... - No.
我们说过要严责  我们就得严责
We said we'd lay down the law, we lay down the law.
我们要贯彻执行
We just have to be consistent about it.
你没坐校车
You're not taking the bus?
好吧  那么
All right, well, listen.
再给我20分钟  我们就回去
Give me maybe another 20 minutes and we'll get out of here.
-好吧  -好吧
- All right. - All right.
很好
Yeah, good.
你瞧  我只是在想
You know, I just think that...
事情总会有解决的办法的
Things have a way of working themselves out.
你啥时候得这奖的
When did you get this?
去年5月的年终总结会上
Last may at the year-end assembly.
他们还给了我那个
They gave me that one, too.
摆最后面那个
The one on the end.
环保意识奖
Environmental consciousness award.
这什么玩意儿
What's that mean?
是说你喜欢回收破易拉罐吗
You, like, recycle cans and shit?
我联系了阿尔布开克杂志社
I contacted the Albuquerque Journal
询问了他们是用什么化学品来漂白纸张
And asked what chemicals they use to bleach their paper.
他们为此专门撰写了一篇文章
They wound up writing an article about it.
干得好  小兄弟
Right on, little bro!
还能把工商界再搞个天翻地覆
Making mad in-roads with the business community.
挺好
All right!
现在  听着
Now, hey, remember,
有些东西靠读书是学不来的
Not all learning comes out of books.
瞧瞧你
Look at you.
我们应该多出去溜达溜达
We should hang out more often.
你瞧  只是
You know, just...
绕绕圈  透透气什么的
Just kick back and chill.
我是说  如果你
I mean, if you ever,
怎么说呢  需要开导的时候
Like, I don't know, need advice.
因为  我的意思是
Because, yo, I mean,
毕竟我什么都曾经历过
I've been through it all. For real.
喂  哥们  你
Hey, man, you...
你会吹长笛的啊
You play the flute?
其实那是短笛
It's a piccolo, actually.
那给来段杰斯罗·塔尔(乐队名)的吧
Dude, play some... play some Jethro Tull.
嘿  小伙们
Hey, guys.
聊得怎么样
How we doing in here?
挺好的
We're good.
嗯  挺好  妈
Yeah. Fine, mom.
行  那就好
Well, that's good.
太  太好了
That's... that's great.
什么情况
What the hell?
瞧这情形
You see this?
我是个罪犯还是咋的
What, am I some criminal or something?
-无所谓啦  -无所谓吗
- Whatever. - Whatever?
你觉得这是无所谓吗
What, you think that's okay?
这就像  我们不能让那个坏蛋
Like, "oh, we can't let that scumbag"
带坏我们的宝贝孩子
"warp the mind of our favorite son."
我是宝贝吗
I'm the favorite?
得了吧
Yeah, right.
他们最常挂在嘴边的是你
You're practically all they ever talk about.
我靠
Oh, snap.
真帅
Awesome.
哥们  是我
Yo, man, it's me.
听着  你的那个货
Hey, listen. You know, that product?
你还有没
You got any more of that?
没了  哥们  行吗
Nah, man, okay?
我不能再免费给了
I'm done giving out freebies.
想要免费的就去找救世军吧
You want charity, go ask the salvation army.
不  没有免费了
No, no charity.
我有个表哥
I got this cousin,
他认识几个款爷
He's got him some rich friends.
他们就在城里
These dudes are in town.
正准备开个聚会呢
They're looking to par-tay.
而你那货真是  太爽了
And your stuff is, like, so sweet.
你觉得怎么样
So what do you say?
要不要再干一笔大的
You up for making some fat stacks?
他们会买下所有的货
Because they'll buy everything you got.
这不是来真的吧
You can't be serious.
你来这干嘛呢
What the hell are you doing here?
我等那臭小子走了后才来的
Yo, I waited till the bowl buster left.
我是说  无意的
I mean, no offense.
谁让你来的
Who sent you?
带窃听器了  来陷害我吗
You wearing a wire? You setting me up?
窃听器  你想要窃听器
A wire? you want a wire?
我倒有个  来跟我老二说吧  傻B
I got a wire. Speak into the mic, bitch!
你脑子进水了吧  窃听器
What the hell's wrong with you? A wire. Jesus.
那你跟谁说了
So who did you tell about...
没人  你咋了  疯了吗
Nobody. What are you, nuts?
那你来干什么
Then why are you here?
我不知道
I don't know.
就是来
To, like...
打个招呼吧
Touch base.
打个招呼
Touch base?
是的  你知道
Yeah, you know...
你把那叫啥来着
What you call...
汇报工作吧
A debrief?
也许我们该
Maybe we could, like...
我觉得我们该汇报下工作了
I thought we could debrief.
汇报工作
Debrief?
哈  你觉得
Wow, that's...
你觉得我们该汇报下工作了
That's what you think we need, to debrief?
是啊  那些事发生后
Yeah, after what happened
看上去似乎该做做汇报了
It just seems like the thing to do.
比如说  你知道的
Kind of, you know, talk about it.
咱跟谁都不能提起的那些事
We can't talk to anybody else.
还有就是  我想
Anyway, that, and I wanted to...
我想告诉你大家有多喜欢
I wanted to tell you how much everybody digs
我们做的冰毒
That meth we cooked.
他们趋之若鹜
Everybody digs the meth...
我们做的
We cooked.
说正经的  我有个兄弟
Seriously, I got...
宁愿自己少块肉
Dudes that would give their left nut
都想再来上点
For a little more.
那挺好
Great.
我想说的是  如果你
I'm just saying, if you ever...
真的看开了的话
Saw your way clear to...
我是说  我们俩
You know, you and I...
可以再制点冰毒啥的
Cooking a little more.
滚出我的家
Get the hell off my property.
-什么  我说说而已嘛  -不许再踏进我家
- What? I'm just saying. - Go and don't come back.
马上滚
Now!
好的
All right.
你知道吗
You know what?
4000大洋
Four grand.
上次那批货卖掉了  这是你的份
Your share from selling that batch.
所以我才来找你
That's why I'm here.
是啊  没错
Yeah, that's right.
我一点都没抽过
I didn't smoke it all.
非小细胞型腺癌
Non-small cell adenocarcinoma.
到了第三期[即中晚期]
Stage 3A,
意味着癌细胞从肺部扩散到了淋巴组织
Which means it's spread from the lung to the lymph nodes.
毫无疑问  已经很严重了
There's no denying it's very serious.
不过这...
But is it...
这是...
It is...
是可以治愈的吧
Curable?
我觉得  能治疗  更合适
I prefer the word "treatable."
但我们采用的治疗方法可以说非常有效
But the treatments we have at our disposal can be very effective.
虽然不能打保票  但我可以说
Without making any promises, I can tell you that
我所要推荐的放疗和化疗
The specific course of radiation and chemotherapy I'm going to suggest
一直都很成功
Has been successful.
在某些病例中
In certain cases,
延长了病人生命  甚至缓解了病情
It prolonged patients' lives and even resulted in remission.
那副作用呢
What about the side effects?
副作用有可能平缓到忽略不计
Well, they can be mild to practically non-existent,
也有可能非常强烈
Or they can be pretty darn awful.
这都是因人而异的
It varies from patient to patient.
典型的有  脱发
Typically, there's hair loss,
化疗开始的几周内就会开始脱发
Which begins a couple of weeks after the start of chemotherapy.
还会觉得特别疲劳  浑身乏力
You may find yourself unusually fatigued, not much energy.
嗜睡  不想起床
You won't want to get out of bed.
因食欲不振  肠胃不适而导致体重下降
You may lose weight due to reduced appetite and certain intestinal issues.
肌肉酸痛  牙龈疼痛出血
Muscle aches and pains, gums get sore and bleed.
当然了  还有可能呕吐
And, of course, there's the possibility of nausea.
不过我们会开些止吐剂  帮助缓解症状
Although, we'll prescribe an anti-emetic and try to counteract that.
还可能刺激肾脏和膀胱
Possible kidney or bladder irritation.
稍有不慎就会引起淤青和流血
You may wind up with increased bruising and bleeding.
还会对性生活造成影响
There may be sexual side effects.
皮肤会变得干燥  易怒
Your skin may become dry and irritated...
你还有什么话说吗
Got anything to say?
你知道这是什么吗
What do you know about that?
-不知道  -这次别想蒙混过关
- Nothing. - That's not going to fly this time.
我们给过你多少机会
How many chances have we given you?
多少次我们就坐在这里
How many times have we sat right here
一次又一次重复着同样的对话
And had the same conversation over and over again
你就这么看着我们  做出一脸无辜的样子
Where you look us in the eye and you plead ignorance,
你玩弄了我们的感情
And you play on our emotions,
就会说好话哄着我们
And you tell us anything you think we want to hear
好让我们再给你一次机会
Just so we'll give you another chance?
你每次都把我们当傻瓜耍着玩
And it makes us feel like fools, every time.
够了  杰西
Enough, Jesse.
到此为止了
Enough.
我们家不允许出现这种东西
We are not going to have this in our house.
我们要你离开这里
We need you to leave.
谢谢你没有告发我
Thanks for not telling on me.
你能还给我吗
You think I could have it back?
顺便说  这大麻也太次了
It's skunk weed anyway.
这病还是很有治愈希望的
You know, this is actually very hopeful.
你听到了吗
Did you hear me?
我说  你这病治愈的希望还是很大的
I said this is really very, very hopeful.
我去打电话告诉他们  下周开始治疗好吗
Can I call them and tell them you'll start next week?
我只是觉得我们该...
I just think that we need to...
再讨论一下  如此而已
Discuss it a little more, that's all.
有什么好讨论的
What is there to discuss?
你要得到最好的治疗
You're going to get the best treatment
而他是这方面的权威
And he's the best.
是关于钱的问题
Well, there's the money discussion.
就这么赔上9万美元
$90,000 out of pocket.
-可能还不止  -总会有办法的  沃尔特
- Maybe more. - There's a way, Walt.
可以贷款  还可以分期付款
There's financing, there's installment plans.
我也可以随时出去工作
I could always go back to work.
沃尔特  总会有办法的
Walt, there's always a way.
好吧
All right.
斯凯勒  即使这个办法行得通
Skyler, say that there is a way.
我们把钱都花下去了  而我
And we spend all that money, and...
我能就这么让你们去扛这一大笔债吗
Am I supposed to leave you with all that debt?
我做不到  我只是不想感情用事罢了
No. I just don't want emotions ruling us.
也许  治疗不是个好办法
Maybe treatment isn't the way to go.
那你为什么不早点死了算了
Then why don't you just fucking die already?
放弃治疗  一了百了
Just give up and die.
给我闪开
Come on, move your ass.
我有什么好担心的
What do I care?
我不担心  我可有最好的律师
Yeah, I'm not worried. I have the best fucking attorney.
我要是对方  现在就该感到害怕了
I would not want to be on the other side of this one...
该死的怎么回事啊
What the hell?
还愣着干嘛  快找人帮忙  快打119啊
What are you doing? Call somebody, call the fire people.
简直难以置信  你知道我这车有多贵吗
I don't believe it. You know how much I paid for that?
这到底怎么回事啊
Why is it doing this?